On ancient ground, at the edge of the world, an evil born in
heaven is about to be unleashed on earth.
The Prophecy is a action, mystery, fantasy film directed by Gregory Widen.
The angel Gabriel comes to Earth to collect a soul which will end the stalemated war
in Heaven, and only a former priest and a little girl can stop him.
Gabriel, played by Christopher Walken.
Thomas Daggett, played by Elias Koteas.
Katherine Henley, played by Virginia Madsen.
Simon, played by Eric Stoltz.
Lucifer, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Rachael, played by Amanda Plummer.
The Prophecy is a 1995 American fantasy thriller horror film starring Christopher
Walken, Elias Koteas, Virginia Madsen, Eric Stoltz, and Viggo Mortensen.
It was written and directed by Gregory Widen in his feature directorial
debut, and is the first film of The Prophecy series.
The film tells the story of the Archangel Gabriel (Walken) and his search for an evil soul on Earth, and a
police detective (Koteas) who unknowingly becomes caught in the middle of an angelic civil war.
It was followed by four sequels.
The tone is intense and mind_bending.